Finding Aid for Alexander Jefferson papers, 1921-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Alexander Jefferson papers 1921-2006 1944-2006
Jefferson, Alexander, 1921-
0712 Aa 2; UAm
Ret. Lt. Col. Alexander Jefferson, pilot and ex-P.O.W., collection of personal papers and records from the Tuskegee Airmen national organization and Detroit Chapter, and the Tuskegee Airmen National Historical Museum in Detroit, Michigan.
6 linear feet
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Alexander Jefferson (donor no. 9786 ) and came to the library September 2006.
The collection is open to research.
Ret. Lt. Col. Alexander Jefferson was born 15 November 1921 in Detroit, MI. He graduated from Clark College in Atlanta, Georgia in 1942 and was working towards a Masters Degree in chemistry from Howard University in Washington, D.C. before entering the Aviation Cadet Program at Tuskegee Army Airfield, graduating in January 1944.
Jefferson fought in World War II as a P-51 fighter pilot in the famed Tuskegee Airmen segregated air force, the "Red-Tail" 332nd Fighter Group, and flew 18 long range escort missions for B-17 and B-24 bombers. Three days before the invasion of Southern France he was shot down by ground fire while strafing radar stations over Toulon, France on 12 August, 1944 and immediately captured by German troops. Jefferson spent five months in Stalag Luft III prison before being transferred to Stalag VIIA near Mooseburg, Germany by way of marching 80 kilometers in sub-zero temperatures and pressed into a "40 and 8" boxcar. Following the war Lt. Col. Jefferson served as an instrument instructor in advance training at Tuskegee Army Air Field and as a Staff Operations and Training Officer of the 9504th Air Recovery Squadron. He was discharged from active duty in 1947 and retired from the reserves in 1969 with the rank of Lieutenant Colonel.
Alexander Jefferson earned a Masters Degree of Education from Wayne University and taught science to elementary school students in Detroit. He retired as assistant principal in 1979. Jefferson was enshrined into the Michigan Aviation Hall of Fame in 1995 and received the Purple Heart in 2004.
The first meeting of the Tuskegee Airmen took place on 14 July 1972 when a small group of veterans gathered in the home of Alexander Jefferson. Tuskegee Airmen Incorporated has since become a large national organization with 48 chapters (as of 2006), with Jefferson serving in the organization in a variety of capacities and making numerous public appearances and speeches.
The Alexander Jefferson papers are divided into five series: Personal Papers, Tuskegee Airmen Incorporated, Tuskegee Airmen Detroit Chapter, Tuskegee Airmen National Historical Museum, and Photographs.
Subjects:
Jefferson, Alexander, 1921-; World War, 1939-1945--Participation, African American.; African American air pilots--History.; United States. Air Force--African Americans.; African Americans in aeronautics.; United States. Army Air Forces. Fighter Group, 332nd.; Prisoners of war--United States.; Tuskegee Airmen, Inc.; Tuskegee Airmen, Inc. Detroit Chapter.; Tuskegee Airmen National Historical Museum.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Jefferson, Alexander, 1921-; United States. Air Force--African Americans.; African Americans in aeronautics.; United States. Army Air Forces. Fighter Group, 332nd.; Tuskegee Airmen, Inc.; Tuskegee Airmen, Inc. Detroit Chapter.; Tuskegee Airmen National Historical Museum.
Contributors:
Young, Coleman A.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Personal Papers
  The Personal Papers series (1.1 linear feet) contains five sub-series: Biographical materials; Correspondence; Personal items; Press; and Public Appearances.
  - Biographical Materials
    The Biographical Materials sub-series includes several biographical summaries and a handful of manuscripts.
    - Biographical Summaries, published undated (Box 1)
    - Congressional Black Caucus Veterans' Braintrust Award 2002 (Box 1)
    - "The Encounter (A True Story)," From NASA Website 2004 (Box 1)
    - "Forgotten Victims: Blacks In The Holocaust," Journal of Negro History, 1992 (Box 1)
      (includes mention of two pilots shot down over Toulon)
    - German P.O.W. Record, 2 photographs (Box 1)
    - Manuscripts
      - "28th St., Clark, Howard, & Army" (Box 1)
      - "As It Happened" (Box 1)
      - Biographical Summaries, dated 1992-2002 (Box 1)
      - Biographical Summaries undated (Box 1)
      - Book Ideas 2005 (Box 1)
      - "If I Knew Then What I Know Now" (Box 1)
      - "The Importance of Education and Educational Experience" (Box 1)
      - "Memoirs as an Ex-P.O.W." (Box 1)
      - "Molding a Black Legacy," 1989 (Box 1)
      - "Reflections On My Life" (Box 1)
      - Remembrance of Interrogation By A German University of Michigan Alumnus (Box 1)
      - Remembrance of Being Shot Down and First Encounter (Box 1)
      - Remembrance of Being Shot Down and Interrogated (Box 1)
    - Michigan Aviation Hall of Fame Enshrinement 1995 (Box 1)
    - Michiganaviation.org biography 2005 (Box 1)
    - Military Order of the World Wars History Book Biography 1992 (Box 1)
    - NASA Website Biography and Career Card (Box 1)
    - Parrish, Noel F., Brig. Gen., Award Nomination (Box 1)
    - Smithsonian National Air and Space Museum Wall of Honor 2003 (Box 1)
    - War Record undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    The Correspondence sub-series dates from 1974 to 2006 and includes correspondence with Coleman Young and other military dignitaries.
    - 1974 with Coleman Young (Box 1)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - 1979 with Brig. Gen. Titus Hall (Box 1)
    - 1984-1987 (Box 1)
    - 1990-1998 (Box 1)
    - 2001-2003 (Box 1)
    - 2004 (Box 1)
    - 2004, 2006 regarding discovery of Capt. Robert Daniels' Plane (Box 1)
    - 2005 (Box 1)
    - 2005 Library of Congress American Folklife Center (Box 1)
    - 2005 Ford Foundation Grant (Box 1)
    - 2005 Maj. Gen. Thomas Cutler (Box 1)
    - 2006 (Box 1)
    - 2006 Alexander Jefferson Crash Site (Box 1)
    - Undated (Box 1)
  - Personal Items
    The Personal Items sub-series includes matters pertaining to the history of Pattengill School and Jefferson's tenure as an Air Force recruiter.
    - Administration of the Estate of Jane White Jefferson 1986 (Box 1)
    - Air Force Association Membership 1977-1981 (Box 1)
    - Air Force Education Symposium 1981 (Box 1)
    - Air Force Recruiting 1980-1986 (Box 1)
    - American Ex-P.O.W. 45th National Convention 1992 (Box 1)
    - American Legion Membership 1996, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Genealogy written By niece Margaret E. Thompson (Box 1)
    - Grixdale Park Property Owners Association 1953-1955, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Marriage Certificate of Parents (photograph), 192[year missing] (Box 1)
    - Michigan Aviation Hall of Fame 1998-2000, 2003 (Box 1)
    - P-51 Pilots Convention 2005 (Box 1)
    - Pattengill Elementary School and Its Surrounding Areas, Student Paper, after 1959 (Box 1)
    - Pattengill School History and Mission Statement (includes P.T.A. 1957-1958 and Staff Directory, 1965-1967) (Box 1)
    - Project Description Of Book [later titled "Red Tailed Captured, Red-Tail Free"] (Box 1)
    - Retirement Party 1979 (Box 1)
    - Stalag Luft III Ballad (Box 1)
    - Stalag Luft III Ex-P.O.W. Organization 1970-1983, 2001 (Box 1)
    - Student Paper About Alexander Jefferson 2003 (Box 1)
  - Press
    - 1977-1989 (Box 1)
    - 1990-1996 (Box 1)
    - 2000 Detroit Free Press, "Faces of the 21st Century" (Box 1)
    - 2000-2003 (Box 1)
    - 2004 Arkansas Democrat Gazette, Purple Heart Recipient (Box 1)
    - 2004-2005 (Box 1)
    - 2005 Book Reviews (Box 1)
    - 2006 (Box 1)
    - Undated (Box 1)
  - Public Appearances
    The Public Appearances sub-series demonstrates Alexander Jefferson's career as a public speaker, running the gamut from primary schools around Southeast Michigan to an International Conference in Germany. This sub-series also includes speech notes, transcripts, and a transcript of a question and answer session following a NASA-sponsored event. Some speech topics are Ret. Lt. Col. Jefferson's experiences as a pilot and prisoner of war in World War II, segregation, and the importance of education.
    - Speech Transcripts
      - circa 1965-1967 African-American Education, Pattengill School, Race Relations (Box 1)
      - 1994 "Be With Us, Lest We Forget," Novi, MI. (Box 1)
      - 1997 Keynote Address, Indianhead Association, Detroit, MI. (Box 1)
      - 2000 "Fight For The Right To Fight," Speech Outline, Vance AFB (Box 1)
      - 2001 Speech Ideas (Box 1)
      - 2001 "Myths, Half-Truths, and Downright Lies," Mayflower Congregational Church, Detroit, MI. (Box 1)
      - 2001 NASA, Centennial of Flight, Speech and Q&A Transcript, Moffet Field, CA. (Box 1)
      - 2002 "Now I Know," Novi, MI. (Box 1)
      - Undated Speeches and Speech Notes (Box 1)
    - 1978-1981 USAF Education Airlift (Box 1)
    - 1981-1987 Career Day, various schools (Box 1)
    - 1983 (Box 1)
    - 1995-2000 (Box 2)
    - 2001 NASA Aero Expo (Box 2)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 2)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 2)
    - 2005 University of Tennessee, East Tennessee Historical Society (Box 2)
    - 2005-2006. (Box 2)
    - 2006 U.S. Army, Perspectives in Military History, Carlisle, PA. (Box 2)
    - 2006 African Americans and Germany International Conference, Westphalian Wilhelms University, Muenster, Germany (Box 2)
- Tuskegee Airmen Incorporated
  The Tuskegee Airmen Incorporated series (3.1 linear feet) comprises seven sub-series: Biographical files; Correspondence; History; Media (press, reviews, and advertisements); Organization; Press; and Public Appearances.
  - Biographical Files
    The Biographical Files sub-series includes information for sixty of Jefferson's fellow Tuskegee Airmen. This includes press clippings, photos, and other various ephemera.
    - Alexander, Buford (Box 2)
    - Anderson, Charles Alfred "Chief," Sr. (Box 2)
    - Archer, Lee A., Jr. (Box 2)
    - Archer, Lee A., Jr.; Brown, Roscoe C.; McGee, Charles (Box 2)
    - Bailer, Kermit (Box 2)
      (includes photograph)
    - Bailey, Charles (Box 2)
    - Baugh, Howard L. (Box 2)
    - Browne, Earnest C. (Box 2)
    - Browne, Roscoe C., Jr., Ph.D. (Box 2)
    - Cargill, Gilbert (Box 2)
    - Carr, Nathaniel (Box 2)
    - Carter, Herbert; McGee, Charles; Macon, Richard; Jefferson, Alexander (Box 2)
    - Carter, Mildred (Hemmons) (Box 2)
    - Chappell, Roy (Box 2)
    - Chase, Bill; Smith, Leon E. (Box 2)
    - Coffey, Cornelius (Box 2)
    - Cole, Alfred E. (Box 2)
    - Davis, Alfonza W. (Box 2)
    - Davis, Benjamin O., Jr. (General)
      - Benjamin O. Davis Aerospace High School (Box 2)
      - Biography 1947 AAF Document (Box 2)
      - Changing The Wind Awards Banquet Program 1991 (Box 2)
      - Film Outline (Box 2)
      - Funeral Announcement and Program 2002 (Box 2)
      - Press
        - 1948 Ebony Magazine (Box 2)
        - 1982-2002 (Box 2)
        - 2002 Obituaries (Box 2)
        - 2006 (Box 2)
        - Undated (Box 2)
    - Decatur, Robert, Judge (Box 2)
    - Desvignes, Russell (Box 2)
    - Dixione, Ario (Box 2)
    - Downs, Walter (Box 2)
    - Driver, Elwood Thomas "Woody" (Box 2)
      (includes four photographs)
    - Ferguson, William (Box 2)
    - Gray, Leo R. (Box 2)
    - Harris, Maceo (includes 1944 AAF Missing Crew Report) (Box 2)
    - Holloman, William Hugo, III (Box 2)
    - Isabelle, Spencer (includes 1946 AAF Death Notice) (Box 2)
    - Jackson, Lewis A., Dr. (Box 2)
    - James, Daniel "Chappie," Jr. (General) (Box 2)
    - Jefferson, Alexander; Macon, Richard; Stewart, Harry T. (Box 2)
    - Lane, Charles (Box 2)
    - Lawrence, Robert (Box 2)
    - Lawson, Herman (Box 2)
    - Lipscomb, Wendell Ralph (Box 2)
    - Macon, Richard (Box 2)
    - Marsh, Donald D. (Box 2)
    - McClenic, William B.; Theus, Lucius (Maj. General) (Box 2)
    - McGee, Charles Edward (Box 2)
    - McKeethen, Lloyd B. (Box 2)
    - Mitchell, George T. (Box 2)
    - Mitchell, Vincent (Box 2)
    - Parrish, Noel (Brig. General) (Box 2)
    - Pierson, Gwynne W (Box 2)
    - Polk, Wardell (Box 2)
    - Purnell, Louis (Box 2)
    - Richardson, Virgil (Box 2)
    - Roberts, George "Spanky" (Box 2)
    - Ross, Mac (Box 2)
    - Ross, Washington (Box 2)
    - Shelton, Forrest, Jr. (Box 2)
    - Smith, Luther (Box 2)
    - Smith, Rothacker (Box 2)
    - Spencer, Chauncey E. (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Harry T. (Box 2)
    - Summers, Dan (Box 2)
    - Terrelonge, Victor (Box 2)
    - Theus, Lucius (Maj. General) (Box 2)
    - Thompson, William "Bill" (Box 2)
    - Tibbs, Howard (Box 2)
    - Wheeler, William "Billy" (Box 2)
    - White, Sherman W., Jr. (Box 2)
    - Whiteside, Albert, Jr. (Box 2)
    - Whitley, Morris D. (Box 2)
    - Williams, Charles T. "Chuck" (Box 2)
    - Wolfe, Robert Lee, Jr. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence
    The Correspondence sub-series dates from 1974 to 2005 and again includes correspondence with Coleman Young. There are also letters pertaining to a dispute within the organization's board of directors.
    - 1974 (Box 2)
    - 1977 with Coleman Young (Box 2)
    - 1989 (Box 2)
    - 1996 (Box 2)
    - 2002 (Box 2)
    - 2004 (Box 2)
    - 2005 Board of Directors Dispute (Box 2)
    - 2005 Congressional Gold Medal (Box 2)
  - History
    The History sub-series includes some full-color books which were distributed at the National Conventions, the 487 page George L. Washington manuscript, several "one-sheets" prepared for media, and a wide variety of other documents.
    - 27th National Convention 1998 Full-color Book, 110 Pages (Box 2)
    - 29th National Convention 2000 Full-color Book, 76 Pages (Box 2)
    - 31st National Convention 2002 Full-color Book, 82 Pages (Box 2)
    - 50th Anniversary Commemorative Bust 1986-1992 (Box 2)
    - 60th Anniversary 2004 Full-color Book, 14 pages (Box 2)
    - 60th Anniversary Reunion 2004 (Box 2)
    - 99th Squadron Roster, AAF Document December 11, 1945 (Box 2)
    - 100th Composite Squadron, Establishment of 2002 (Box 2)
    - 332nd Fighter Group "Personal Narrative," By Capt. Ray B. Ware, AAF Document September 9, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Aerial Victories of The 332nd Fighter Group 1944-1945 (Box 2)
    - African American Army Nurses of World War II (Box 2)
    - African Americans Voices of Triumph Perseverance, Excerpt of (Box 2)
    - Aircraft 31-25751 A Time To Remember (Box 2)
    - American Casualties List 2005 (Box 2)
    - America's Lonely Eagles Membership Pamphlet (Box 2)
    - Army Air Corps Black Military Personnel Statistics 1942-1946 (Box 2)
    - Bibliography, 2 items (Box 2)
    - Black Americans In Military Aviation Exhibit and Protest by Alexander Jefferson and the NAACP, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Black Wings: The History of the American Black In Aviation Pamphlet, Sloan Museum, Flint, MI. (Box 2)
    - Black Wings, Reception and Dinner, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Combat Deaths 2005 (Box 2)
    - Combat Record of Black Airmen June 9, 1945 (Box 2)
    - "Commemorating the Airmen at Moton Field," Resource Study, Emory University, National Park Service 1998 including full-color booklet, Questionnaire Results (Box 2)
    - Congressional Gold Medal Reception and Dinner 2006 (Box 2)
    - Congressional Gold Medal Senate Bill 2005 (Box 2)
    - Congressional Record, "The Negro Soldier," 1946 (Box 2)
    - Dedication of Memorial, Colorado Springs, CO. 1988 (Box 2)
    - False Claims of Tuskegee Airmen Imposters 2004 (Box 3)
    - Flag Officers Banquet, Washington D.C. 1982 (Box 3)
    - Freeman Field Incident 1945-1946, 1996 (Box 3)
      (includes AAF and USAF documents, press clippings)
    - Frontiers of Flight Museum Honors The Tuskegee Airmen 2005 (Box 3)
    - Graduates of Army Field Advanced Flying School 1942-1946 (Box 3)
    - Graduates of Civilian Pilot Training Program 1941 (Box 3)
    - Henry, Milton, Petition To Set Aside Wrongful Court Martial 1943-1944, 1993 (Box 3)
    - "History of 332nd Fighter Group," 1948 USAF Document (Box 3)
    - "History of 2143rd AAF Base Unit and Tuskegee Army Air Field," 1945 AAF Document (Box 3)
    - "How Many Tuskegee Airmen?" Theopolis "Ted" Johnson 2000 (Box 3)
    - "Invisible Wings: An Annotated Bibliography of Blacks In Aviation 1916-1993" excerpt of, Betty Kaplan Gubert, compiler (Box 3)
    - The Last Hurrah 1949, 2004-2005 (Box 3)
      (including illustrated book and press clippings)
    - Manuscripts
      - "A Brief History of The 332nd 'Red Tail' Fighter Group," Morris S. Whitley (Box 3)
      - "American Black In Aviation" (Box 3)
      - "An Abbreviated History of The American Black in World War II," Robert L. Tinsley (Box 3)
      - Brief Histories, 27 items (Box 3)
      - "The Do-Do Verses" (Box 3)
      - "The Enlisted Men" (Box 3)
      - "History of Black Pilots," Chauncey Spencer (Box 3)
      - "History of Military and Civilian Pilot Training of Negroes at Tuskegee, Alabama 1939-1945 George L. Washington, 487 pages (Box 3)
      - "Participants In The Noble Experiment," Theopolis Johnson 1996, 1998 (Box 3)
      - "Songs of the 99th and Tuskegee Airmen" (Box 3)
      - "Tuskegee Airmen, Inc." (Box 3)
    - Mighty 8th Airforce Heritage Museum Exhibit 1998 (Box 3)
    - Military Group, Squadron Fact Sheets (Box 3)
    - Moton Field Restoration 2005 (Box 3)
    - National Archives Release Tuskegee Airmen History 1997 (Box 3)
    - "Ode To Red Tails," William "Billy" Wheeler (Box 3)
    - Pilot's Day Party in Cattolica, Italy, Invitation 1945 (copy) (Box 3)
    - Plane Names (Box 3)
    - Planes Used By The Tuskegee Airmen (Box 3)
    - Red Tail Project Website 2003 (Box 3)
    - Report of Major Accident, John Daniels, Pilot 1946 AAF Document (Box 3)
    - The Ron Spriggs Exhibit of Kentucky's Known Tuskegee Airmen Cadets, Nicholasville, KY., 2005 (Box 3)
    - Sickle-Cell Study 1977-1980 (Box 3)
    - "Story of 332nd Fighter Group and Wing," AAF Document (Box 3)
    - Harry S Truman Recognition 1991 (Box 3)
    - Tuskegee Airmen Achievement Award, University of Michigan Military Officer Education Program Committee 2002 (Box 3)
    - Tuskegee Airmen History Project, University of Michigan 1995 (Box 3)
    - Tuskegee Airmen National Historic Site Lease 2002 (Box 3)
    - Tuskegee Airmen National Historic Site Ephemera, 5 items (Box 3)
    - Tuskegee Airmen Oral History Project, Howard University 1996 (Box 3)
    - Tuskegee Airmen P.O.W.'s, M.I.A.'s, and Killed In Action (Box 3)
    - Tuskegee Angels of World War II Website 2006 (Box 3)
    - Tuskegee Rickenbacker Foundation Pledge Ask (Box 3)
    - Tuskegee University Honorary Degrees 2006 (Box 3)
    - Victories, Recorded by Sergeant Whitley 1944-1945, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Wall Of Honor Panel, Dulles International Airport 2003 (Box 3)
    - Waniek, Marilyn Nelson, Dr., Proposal to Name Poetess Laureate 1994 (Box 3)
    - Western Region Tuskegee Archive, Riverside, CA. 2006 (Box 3)
  - Media (Press, Reviews, and Advertisements)
    The Media (press, reviews, and advertisements) sub-series relates to Tuskegee Airmen movies and books. This series also has records from a trip to Lucasfilm's Skywalker Ranch and correspondence related to this partnership.
    - "A Sparrow Has Wings," book by John W. Gibson (Box 3)
    - Auntie Eleanor, regarding film (Box 3)
    - Documentary Proposal: Black Eagles. Stories of the Tuskegee Airmen, 1995 (Box 3)
    - "Black Flyers in World War II," book by Sgt. William C. Ferguson 1988 (Box 3)
    - "Black Knights: The Story of the Tuskegee Airmen," book by Lynn M. Homan and Thomas Reilly (Box 3)
    - "Double V," book by Dr. William M. Womack, correspondence with the University of Michigan Press 1993 (Box 3)
    - Editorial Regarding Lack of Tuskegee Airmen Movie 1975 (Box 3)
    - From The Beginning regarding short film (Box 3)
    - Hart's War, regarding 2002 movie (Box 3)
    - "The Invisible Soldier," Book by Mary Penick Motley (Box 3)
    - Lucasfilm
      - 1990 Agreement with Tuskegee Airmen (Box 3)
      - 1990 Press Clipping Regarding Lucas' Next Film (Box 3)
      - 2005 Correspondence With Janice Yvonne Hecht (Box 3)
        (including 1990 documents)
      - 2005 George Lucas Letter of Introduction (Box 3)
      - 2005 George Lucas Mentions Tuskegee Airmen in Time (Box 3)
      - 2005 Tuskegee Airmen Visit To Lucasfilm's Skywalker Ranch (Box 3)
    - Movie Controversy correspondence 1974-1975 (Box 3)
    - National Tuskegee Airmen History Book 1995 (Box 3)
    - Saving America Documentary, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Spookwaffe Movie (Box 3)
    - "The Tuskegee Airmen," Book by Charles E. Francis (Box 3)
    - The Tuskegee Airmen, HBO Movie, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Tuskegee Airmen: American Heroes, Documentary, 1996 (Box 3)
    - "The Tuskegee Airmen Mutiny At Freeman Field," Book by Lt. Col. James C. Warren 2006 (Box 3)
    - The Tuskegee Experiment, Documentary Proposal, 1993 (Box 3)
    - "Tuskegee Junction," Signed Paintings by Robert Bailey (Box 3)
    - Unsung Heroes: The Tuskegee Airmen of World War II, Play, 1997 (Box 3)
    - "War Tales," Book by Don Moore 2004 (Box 3)
    - "Wee Pals Salute African-Americans In The Miltary Past & Present," Comic Book by Morrie Turner, including book (Box 3)
  - Organization
    The Organization records consist of membership lists, a record of resolutions from the 1990's, and items concerning most of the national conventions held by Tuskegee Airmen Incorporated.
    - 501-C-3 1978 (Box 3)
    - Annual Report 1994-1995 (Box 3)
    - Articles Of Incorporation 1975 (Box 3)
    - Black History Month Schedule 1984 (Box 3)
    - Board Of Directors Meeting Minutes 1975-1978 (Box 3)
    - Committee Appointments
      - 1972-1975 (Box 3)
      - 1980-1985 (Box 3)
      - 1990-1999 (Box 3)
    - Company Grade And Non-Commissioned Officers Panel 1975 (Box 3)
    - Constitution and By-Laws
      - 1974-1975 (Box 3)
      - 1983, 1987, 1989 (Box 3)
      - 1993, 1997 (Box 3)
      - Undated (Box 3)
    - Corporate Luncheon 1995 (Box 3)
    - Election of Officers Undated (Box 3)
    - Ephemera, 4 items (Box 3)
    - Establishment of National Headquarters 1997 (Box 3)
    - Gillead, Leroy, Foundation 2004 (Box 3)
    - Goals 1998 (Box 3)
    - History of National Tuskegee Airmen Outline and Questionnaire (Box 3)
    - Independent Advisory Group 1998 (Box 3)
    - Installment Of Officers Invocation by Rev. Otis Sanders 1973 (Box 3)
    - Logo Dispute 1993 (Box 3)
    - Lonely Eagles Memorial Service 2000 (Box 3)
    - Membership Application (Box 3)
    - Membership Lists
      - 1969 (Box 3)
      - 1974 (Box 3)
      - 1979 (Box 3)
      - 1990 (Box 3)
    - Message From The President 2003 (Box 3)
    - National Conventions 1972-2006, 28 folders (Box 4)
    - Military Awards 2001 (Box 4)
    - National Headquarters Update 1997 (Box 4)
    - National Historic Site Sample Letter to Congress 1998 (Box 4)
    - National Life Membership (Box 4)
    - Newsletters
      - 1944 (Box 4)
      - 1973 (Box 4)
      - 1980-1989 (Box 4)
      - 1990-1999 (Box 4)
      - 2000-2005 (Box 4)
    - O'Dennis, Samuel, Dismissal 1998 (Box 4)
    - "Original" Tuskegee Airmen, use of 1993 (Box 4)
    - National Programs (Box 4)
    - Petition for Tuskegee Airmen Inclusion In History Books (Box 4)
    - Reparations Memo 2004 (Box 4)
    - Resolutions
      - 1987 (Box 4)
      - 1991-1995 (Box 4)
      - 1996-1997 (Box 4)
      - 1998-2000 (Box 4)
      - Undated (Box 4)
      - Resolution Template (Box 4)
    - Statement of Condition 1985-1986 (Box 4)
    - Student Essay Contest 2005 (Box 4)
    - Suggested Reading List (Box 4)
    - Support of Buffalo Soldiers Monument 1992 (Box 4)
    - Scholarship Fund
      - Annual Report 1984, 1985 (Box 4)
      - Application 1994, 2004 (Box 4)
      - Case Statement (Box 4)
      - Contributions Received (Box 4)
      - Letter Of Intent (Box 4)
      - Pamphlet (Box 4)
    - Ways And Means Committee Report 1996 (Box 4)
  - Press